# **Dominic Frei**

### **Senior Software Engineer**

+353 83 433 28 38 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dominicfrei/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/dominicfrei/</a>

<u>business.dominic.frei@gmail.com</u> <u>https://github.com/DominicFrei</u>



### Introduction

The quality of work is mainly influenced by three factors: experience, passion, and repetition.

For the past 10+ years I worked mainly on iOS apps. Ever since my youth I was interested in games though. While still being active as an iOS developer I am also getting into games development with Unity lately.

Therefore, I am available in both areas and would describe myself as a senior iOS and junior Unity developer.

### **Job History**

#### 06/2016 – Present Co-Founder and Co-CEO of Dewango GmbH, Potsdam, Germany

o Client project: Audi Business Innovation GmbH, Munich, Germany

Project: Car configuration app used to visualise Audi Sports cars on a Unity3D VR application

Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8vJFv4h8UF4

Role: iOS Developer

Tasks: Coding & Tests (Swift), CI (Fastlane & Jenkins), Scrum Master, releases to the Audi Dealers

Client project: A1 Telekom Austria AG, Linz, Austria

Project: Client facing all in one app used by over 5,000,000 customers

Link: <a href="https://www.a1.net/mein-a1-app">https://www.a1.net/mein-a1-app</a>

Role: iOS Developer

Tasks: Coding & Tests (Swift), Software Architecture, CI (Fastlane & Jenkins)

Client project: Science Digital Didactics GmbH, Potsdam, Germany

Project: Learning Games for pupils Role: Product Owner, Unity Developer Tasks: User Stories, Coding in C#

Client project: Bürgerbus-Verein Olfen e.V., Olfen, Germany

Project: Backoffice software for organising bus services in Olfen

Link: <a href="https://www.buergerbus-software.de/">https://www.buergerbus-software.de/</a> Role: Product Owner, iOS Developer

Tasks: User Stories, Requirements Engineering, Software Development (Swift)

Client project: Praxisfux GmbH, Berlin, Germany

Project: Marketplace for medical equipment, available on both Android and iOS

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.praxisfux.praxisfux&hl=en\_IE

Role: Product Owner, Xamarin Developer (C#)

Tasks: User Stories, Coding & Tests

Client project: Huf Secure Mobile GmbH, Velbert, Germany

Project: whitelabeling solution for car rental services and car sharing (locating and opening cars)

Link: https://huf-sixsense.com/oem/beschreibung-2/

Role: iOS Developer

Tasks: Coding & Tests (Swift)

#### 10/2015 – 12/2017 Freelance Software Developer

Client project: Red Bull AG, Salzburg, Austria

Project: Enhancements and Fixes for several internal audit apps

Role: iOS Developer

Tasks: Coding & Tests (ObjectiveC), Architecture

Client project: Red Bull AG, Salzburg, Austria

Project: Unified iOS framework for all internal audit apps

Role: iOS Developer

Tasks: Coding & Tests (ObjectiveC), Architecture

Client project: Audi AG, München, Germany
Project: Car configuration app for dealers (iPad)

Link: <a href="https://ifworlddesignguide.com/entry/128699-audi-car-configurator">https://ifworlddesignguide.com/entry/128699-audi-car-configurator</a>

Role: iOS Developer (ObjectiveC)

Tasks: Implementation of features and bug fixes

#### 01/2011 - 09/2015 arconsis IT-Solutions GmbH, Karlsruhe, Germany

o Client project: **Daimler AG**, Stuttgart, Germany

Project: All in one solution for customer vehicle management Link: <a href="https://www.mercedes-benz.com/en/mercedes-me/">https://www.mercedes-benz.com/en/mercedes-me/</a>

Role: Java Developer

Tasks: Coding & Tests, CI (Maven & Jenkins), Assistant Scrum Master

Client project: Payleven Holding GmbH (now sumup), Berlin, Germany

Project: iOS App for credit card payments using the smartphone

Link: <a href="https://sumup.com/">https://sumup.com/</a>

Role: iOS Developer (ObjectiveC)

Tasks: Coding

#### 05/2010 - 12/2010 Circle8 Event GmbH, Groß-Gerau, Germany

Event Manager & Software Developer (Visual Basic)

Projects: Several events in the medical area

Tasks: Organising Events, Creating Evaluation Sheets (automated via Visual Basic)

#### 

 Apprenticeship as part of the B.Sc. program Role: Software Developer (Java + iOS)

## **Education & Training**

04/2015 Professional Scrum Master

https://www.scrum.org/certificates/141986

04/2015 Professional Scrum Product Owner

https://www.scrum.org/certificates/141987

09/2007 - 02/2010 B.Sc. in Computer Science

University of Applied Sciences, Darmstadt, Germany

# Speaker, Lecturer, Author

03/2013 Workshop 'iOS Fundamentals'

Mobile Technology Conference, Munich, Germany

https://arconsis.com/unternehmen/aktuelles/mtc-2013-03

09/2012 – 03/2013 Lecture 'Practice in Software Development'

Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Karlsruhe, Germany

https://arconsis.com/unternehmen/aktuelles/kit-workshop-reihe

07/2011 Article 'Mobile Gateways'

Mobile Technology Magazine

https://arconsis.com/unternehmen/aktuelles/mtm-mobile-gate

### References

(can be provided on request but are not listed publicly for privacy reasons)